Thomas Kroell

9 Ottley Drive Kidbrooke London (UK) SE39FT

+44 (0) 777 149 3959

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomaskroell

Portfolio: https://bit.ly/3rLJSWi

Skills

Thomas has 20 years of experience designing digital products and experiences for a range of industries and clients, most notable being Oracle, Vodafone, HSBC, Unilever and Tungsten Network.

Specialising in product design, customer experience, and automation, with a passion for building products that improve our lives. He has worked with teams of all sizes, building relationships, sharing knowledge & providing honest feedback.

Experience

Oracle / Senior Consultant - UX Specialist

JUN 2022 - CURRENT, LONDON (UK)

Facilitating workshops with Oracle customers to understand their drivers to build or improve current applications on the cloud. Using various design thinking technichiques to collaboratively understand end users and their outcomes to help ideate solutions that are human focused, technically feasible to develop and align to business outcomes. Using Figma and various design systems to build prototypes for customer feedback and final designs to ensure smooth handover of UIs for development. More recently I have been involved in internal innovation projects which showcase Oracle's Cloud, Blockchain and NFT technology.

Tungsten Network (B2B SAAS) / Head of Network Products & UX JAN 2022 - MAY 2022, LONDON (UK)

Leading the product UX and strategy of financial products that drive customer adoption of electronic invoicing for enterprises in all industries and regions. Facilitating company wide workshops to help drive requirements gathering using design thinking methodologies. Helping to define product vision and coaching product managers to improve backlog priortisation by focusing on customer empathy and outcomes.

Tungsten Network (B2B SAAS) / Senior UX Designer

MAR 2020 - DEC 2021, LONDON (UK)

Managing customer research and analysis activities to develop personas and journey maps. Facilitating company-wide design thinking workshops to identify user needs and brainstorming new ideas, define back office processes and how they affect the user experience. Creating prototypes for testing and validation both internally and externally.

Working closely with product owners, BA's, solution architects, angular and salesforce developers to define and priortise the product backlog, building and iterating on various products, while promoting the needs of the user at all stages. Presenting updates to stakeholders and the wider organisation, gathering feedback, and ensuring alignment.

Autotrip (B2B SAAS) / Senior UX Designer

APR 2019 - DEC 2019, LONDON (UK)

Automated mileage tracking and expense management platform. Leading the end-to-end design of their SAAS platform and mobile app. Key tasks included modernising the design system to improve quality and consistency across multiple platforms, running research to validate ideas and gather ideas for product enhancements. Working collaboratively with engineering and product, while presenting updates to key stakeholders.

King Kroell Design / Co-Founder - Digital Director

SEP 2008 - FEB 2019, DURBAN (SA)

Co-founded a full-service digital agency with clients in the financial, FMCG, and education sectors. Tasks included understanding client needs, designing and building products, presenting to stakeholders, managing designers and developers as well as day-to-day business operations.

Mr Price Group / Interaction Designer

JUL 2005 - AUG 2008, DURBAN (SA)

Designing in-store interactive interfaces for South Africa's largest fashion and sports retailer. Working with the developers using emerging technology to realise the final products.

Clearwater / Designer

JAN 2002 - JUN 2005, JOHANNESBURG (SA)

Storyboarding and animation television promotions working from initial brief to conceptualisation and final product working collaboratively with editors & 3D animators.

_

Education

Dublin Institute of Technology / First Class Honours Degree in Innovation,

Technology & Design

JAN 2018 - DEC 2018, REMOTE

- Leadership & Management
- Industry, Entrepreneurship, Creativity & Innovation
- International Industry Team & Entrepreneur Team Projects
- User Experience (UX) & Solutions Design
- Computational Thinking (Problem Solving Science)
- Agile Methodologies & Technical Project Management
- Digital Product Management, Data Insights & Growth Hacking

Mediatek / Higher Diploma in Digital Design

JAN 1999 - DEC 2001, DURBAN (SA)

- History of Graphic Design
- Fine Art Drawing
- Design & Layout (Photoshop & Illustrator)
- Web Development (Dreamweaver, Flash & Fireworks)
- Video Editing (Final Cut Pro)
- Animation (After Effects)

Certifications

SAP / Building Better Products with a Human-Centered Product Backlog

ISSUED - DEC 2022

IBM / Enterprise Design Thinking Co-Creator

ISSUED - AUG 2020

IBM / Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

ISSUED - APR 2020

Hasso Plattner / Human Centered Design Certificate

ISSUED - JAN 2018

Skills

Human-Centered Design

Process & methodology, User advocacy, Problem focus

User Research & Analysis

Methodology, Usability testing, Synthesis, Competitor research, Analysis of data, UX metrics

Product Thinking

Domain and business knowledge, Requirements definition, Ideation

Interaction Design

Interface structure & layout, Workflows, UX patterns, Accessibility, Prototyping & Wireframes, HTML & CSS

Interface Design

Typography, UX writing, Iconography & Illustration, Design systems & specs

UX Auditing & Quality Assurance

Usability evaluation, Heuristic review, Design QA

UX Leadership

Mentoring & Feedback, UX Vision & Strategy, Process optimisation, Advocating UX, Hiring

Project Management

Planning, Meeting deadlines, Time & Task management

Communication & Collaboration

Presentations, Giving & receiving feedback, Building relationships

Tools

Design & Prototyping

Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, Adobe XD

Collaboration & Ideation

Miro, Mural, FigJam, MS Teams

Project Management

Jira, Confluence, MS Word, MS Excel, MS Teams, Zoom